Hello! In this episode of Bug Bounty Reports
Explained, I will cover my own bug - a $1,500
SSRF in Stripe. And the good thing
about explaining my own reports
is that not only I will tell you what the
bug was but also, how I chose the target,
how I tested it, what tools did I use
and so on. So, enjoy the explanation.
Before I start, a quick announcement about BBRE
Premium. From June, the price goes up. It doesn't
affect current members so if you subscribe in May,
you will lock in the current, low price, forever.
I also migrated BBRE Premium to a new platform
recently and now you can subscribe using PayPal.
If you've been thinking about it for a while,
this is the best time to join BBRE Premium.
Smokescreen is Stripe's open-source tool
that proxies traffic to the external world.
In simple words, I have integrations that wait for
new BBRE Premium subscribers. When you subscribe,
Stripe's server finds what webhooks I've configured
for this event and sends the request with that
information to my server. Where is smokescreen in
this process? It's between Stripe server and the
external world. It makes sure that if I will add,
let's say a cloud metadata endpoint or localhost
as the webhook address, no request will be sent
there. Only the public Internet is allowed.
The particular behavior is based on smokescreen
rules that Stripe's developers created. When doing
my 100 hours bug bounty challenge on Stripe I, saw
very early that the whole organization's GitHub is
in scope. But at the beginning, I did not want to
test smokescreen. The idea of bypassing domain or
IP validation in a tool that's created strictly
for this purpose, seemed like a tall order. I
prefer to attack applications where developers
don't expect it. In this case, it was an eye
to eye duel. But after about 70 hours and weeks
without finding a bug, I decided to take a look.
It's an open-source tool so instead of blindly
adding another webbook endpoints, I prefer to set
up my environment and, apart from just reading the
code, debug the application as it runs. I set it
up on MacOS without any VMs or containers. This is
the access control list that I used for testing.
And I have no idea what these services, projects
and roles mean. I only used default rules because
the same code is used for comparisons anyway. I
was switching between allowlists and denylists.
And this is my config file which just makes sure
that I don't have to use any role, whatever it is.
And finally, this is the curl
command to send the request
through the proxy. If it's denied you get an
error, otherwise you just see example.com.
The first thing I wanted to check was DNS
rebinding. I spent several hours understanding the
protections as is programmed the way I've never
seen before but I wasn't able to find anything
wrong there. So I went on and I wanted to find
the code responsible for comparing domain names.
So first, I noticed checkIfRequestShouldBeProxied
function. So I put a breakpoint there. But
all it does is call checkACLsForRequest and
handles its response. So I jumped into that
function. It also handles some metrics,
logging but it does not contain the logic
of comparing a domain or an IP address.
So I stepped into the Decide function
which sounds more interesting. This one checks
different rules one by one and finally, there is
the hostMatchesGlob function which contains the
actual comparison of one domain to the other.
Of course, the first time I was doing that, it
took me much more time to figure all this out
and I was also checking out what other functions
are doing. The hostMatchesGlob function takes 2
arguments: host and domainGlob. Host
is our, potentially malicious, host.
domainGlob is the rule - it can be a literal
domain or a domain with wildcard subdomains. This
function only checks if those match and it does
not care whether it's an allowlist or denylist.
When the domainGlob is not a wildcard there
is a simple == comparison - as simple as that.
If there is a wildcard, it checks if our host
ends with the domainGlob. So these rules are
quite strict. I did not come up with a way to
bypass an allowlist. But what about a denylist?
Have you ever noticed that when making a DNS
query, there is always the dot at the end?
For a long time, I didn't really care what
it means but it's actually quite significant.
DNS is divided into zones. If you create your
own zone, you have control over DNS inside.
The Internet is under the root zone indicated by:
the trailing dot at the end. So when you visit
example.com. with the trailing dot at the end,
it's a proper, absolute domain name. But usually,
you visit example.com without the dot. From HTTP
or rather HTTPS protocol standpoint, some websites
work with both but others, including mine, don't
work with HTTPS with trailing dots. Without the
dot, it's a relative domain name but the dot
is implicitly appended in your DNS searchlist.
So coming back to the validation - by using the
trailing dot, you could bypass domain deny list.
We can confirm this by stepping into the function
and evaluating that host and domainGlob are not
equal in this case. The same attack works if
the rule forbids traffic to a wildcard subdomain.
Before I submitted the report, I've checked
if any tools like curl, python's requests or
browsers will strip this dot when making a request
but no. So what can you do by bypassing a domain
denylist? The truth is this is much less impactful
than bypassing IP denylist. But that's what I like
about testing open-source tools. Not only do
I have the local debugging setup but also,
I have more possibilities. You see, if I was
only testing stripe.com, there would either
be an SSRF there or not - in this case not. But when
testing an open-source tool that's also used by
other organizations, you only need to find
one configuration where the bug exists.
Of course, it can't be a super unlikely
scenario but you still have much more freedom.
So even though this was only exploitable in a
specific configuration, Stripe rewarded me with
$500 of base payout + $1,000 bonus for finding the
bug in the critical piece of the infrastructure.
As for the fix, dots are now trimmed from the
right before the comparison. We can see that
when using the same command as previously, host
and domainGlob are still not the same but the new,
trimmed variables are so the attack is not
possible. Also, the domains are lowercased
before the comparison. I spent a while trying to
come up with some kind of unicode collision attack
on this lowercasing process but I couldn't
make the attack work. If you want to learn
more about debugging, check out my presentation
from NahamCon about the topic. Also I'm covering
debugging in BBRE Premium, if you want to check
it out go to https://bbre.dev/premium. Just make
sure to join before the price rises! For
now thank you for watching and goodbye!